<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Max Makes Stuff!</title>
    <description>I make stuff! Games and graphics mostly!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 22:05:49 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 22:05:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cargo (In Development)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo&lt;/strong&gt; is a cross country car chase adventure game that I am directing, inspired by classic european cinema, comic books and animation, 
and employing a variety of novel procedural generation technologies, to generate beautiful landscapes on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/CargoRendered2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Rendered Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/CargoRendered1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Rendered Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work in development, not representative of final product&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;prototyping&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s Grand Theft Auto meets Mario Kart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cargo is an explosive, procedurally generated, run based car chase adventure, designed to throw you almost instantly into incredible and
unlikely scenarios. We’ve spent a huge amount of time bending the physics engine to our will, creating a highly reactive, approachable and fun
style of gameplay designed to highlight and exaggerate the drama of an over the top anime car chase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/CargoJump.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CargoJump.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/CargoDriving.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CargoDriving.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototype Footage, not representative of final product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;technology&quot;&gt;Technology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cargo is being built on a stack of novel procedural generation techniques, optimised towards creating believable stylised environments, and roads
carefully tuned for optimal playability, while being able to generate instantly and progressively at runtime, while the game is being played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/roadGeneration.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using a combination of techniques, levels are orchestrated with large scale, constraint driven ‘wave function collapse’ solvers,
terrain is formed using GPU based stamp, noise and erosion systems, and playable roads are laid out using a highly constrained variant of A* pathfinding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools and systems are still in development, and I’m very excited to do a deep dive on how all of these systems work together in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Cargo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Cargo</guid>
        
        <category>Director</category>
        
        <category>Designer</category>
        
        <category>Programmer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Desta: The Memories Between</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desta: The Memories between&lt;/strong&gt; is a turn based strategy game with a unique spin. Developed by ustwo Games and relased for Mobile, PC and Switch, 
you can find out more about this game at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.destagame.com/&quot;&gt;destagame.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/DestaScreenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desta Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototyping&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this project I served as a prototype designer, designing and proving the initial mechanics and gameplay systems via rapid prototyping (left),
that were then used as a template for the final product (right) made by the production team .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/destaPrototype.gif&quot; alt=&quot;destaPrototype.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/destaFinal.gif&quot; alt=&quot;destaPrototype.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mechanically it is a unique mixture of traditional turn based tactics, and playground sports game. Instead of weapons, points (or damage in the final game) can only be scored
by throwing a ball, which for us achieved three core affordances&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It provided a natural random element which helped keep the strategy elements interesting and dynamic, allowing for unexpected failures and happy accidents.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It introduced a ‘ball economy’, balls are required to attack and can be dropped or passed from player to player. Attacking may even provide the enemy with much needed resources, leading to interesting and unique scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a game designed for mobile, it took the largest perceived weakness of the genre, the chunkiness of navigating menus and selecting targets, and replaced it with a fun and engaging input mechanic that felt great on device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many other things changed throughout production, I am personally very proud that the core mechanics that we set proved to be so robust that outside of some small tweaks, and a lot of additions, made it to the final game practically unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;graphics&quot;&gt;Graphics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also provided tech art support and consultancy towards the end of the project.
One fun challenge was the clouds this was a late addition and my performance budget was essentially zero, we could not afford any real time ray marching or even transparency and the clouds
had to be rotatable in 3D space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a custom ray marcher was written that would filter and bake that information directly to the existing vertex data, generating this soft scattered lighting that characterises much
of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/cloudsHard.png&quot; alt=&quot;clouds hard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/cloudsSoft.png&quot; alt=&quot;clouds soft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before:&lt;/strong&gt; previous, unsuccessful texture based attempts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After:&lt;/strong&gt; with my raymarched vertex lighting&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Desta</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Desta</guid>
        
        <category>Designer</category>
        
        <category>Prototyper</category>
        
        <category>Technical Artist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alba: A Wildlife Adventure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alba is a small open world ‘chillectathon’, that see’s you play Alba, a young girl on holiday with her grandparents on a beautiful spanish island.
On Alba’s adventures on Pinar del Mar will see her take on animal photography, wildlife preservation and even uncovering grand political conspiracies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by ustwo Games and relased for Mobile, PC and Switch,
you can find out more about this game at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.albawildlife.com/&quot;&gt;albawildlife.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Not only have ustwo created a world that is stunning to look at, but they’ve crafted a narrative that boldly shouts that this girl can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/albaPhone.png&quot; alt=&quot;Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/alba-wildlife-adventure-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;landscape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work on this project was primarily as a Graphics Programmer and Technical artist, and my focus was split between &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;a.&lt;/strong&gt; making the game look as beautiful as authentic as possible (easy) and &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;b.&lt;/strong&gt; making an ambitious open world game run on &lt;em&gt;ancient&lt;/em&gt; mobile hardware (less easy). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;graphics&quot;&gt;Graphics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work on Alba involved a lot of fun elements that helped bring the natural world of Pinar del Mar to life. Countless natural effects,
a dynamic time of day system, skies, clouds, plants, terrains, a huge number of systems go into running and open world like this efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/albaNightDuck.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Night&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/duckweed.gif&quot; alt=&quot;duckweed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On of the systems I’m proudest of is the oceans and their interaction with the island. This is something that most games will fake, cheat or sidestep
completely but we really wanted to do something special here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/waves.gif&quot; alt=&quot;waves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our level design tools were semi procedural, and the island layout was in flux, redesigns and the shape of the coastline changing often, we
knew that whatever solution we used would have to be automatic, procedural on top of being beautiful and performant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our eventual solution utilises a variety of dense data textures generated at compile time, using signed distance fields, height maps, pre baked noise and a 
sort of modified, velocity aware flood fill (our secret sauce), to generate waves that would believably flow into shore side terrain, while being completely
stateless and lightning fast to render.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alba also had to support some particularly old, early 2010s era mobile hardware, so we had to make sure that we could achieve all of this in a format that
would be able to gracefully scale down the performance spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/AlbaIsland.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AlbaIsland.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the world of Alba is compact, it is incredibly dense, and open in a way that didn’t allow us to hide much at any given time. Almost 
every part of the game is potentially visible from every other part of the island at all times and The design of the game meant that 
almost everything had to be loaded into memory at once!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the work done in this field is hopefully invisible to the user, but Alba involved a LOT of memory optimsation,
a lot of investment into instancing systems including a custom compute based grass system, a system for baking lightmaps while preserving our
dynamic time of day and a lot of work with the art team to help them optimise assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/albaTerrain.gif&quot; alt=&quot;albaTerrain.gif&quot; /&gt;
Our terrain system was optimised for maximum interest with the minimum number of texture reads.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Alba</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Alba</guid>
        
        <category>Technical Artist</category>
        
        <category>Programmer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>APART (In Development)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APART&lt;/strong&gt; is a poetic adventure that finds you controlling a tiny spinning wheel, somewhere between animal and machine,
a minuscule character in a vast abstract world of odd shapes and strange creatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by contemporary ceramics, brutalist architecture and the aesthetics of Genetic Locomotion Experiments, 
this project is a collaboration between myself an The Line Animation, with myself leading development and 
rendering needed to match the ambition and incredible vividness of the concepts
and direction of director &lt;strong&gt;Bjorn-Erik Aschim&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apartRolling.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-game&quot;&gt;The Game&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart is a deeply physics led game, so all of the movement is fluid and dynamic. You have a real sense of momentum as you blast over sand dunes or fling yourself off pieces of architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s like Tony Hawk Pro Skater meets Salvador Dali.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world is inspired in equal parts by contemporary structure, brutalist architecture and the skate park bowls of my youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/unnamed.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/ApartTonyHawk.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Skateboarding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/meanwhile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meahwile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rendering-and-adaptation&quot;&gt;Rendering and Adaptation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart takes place in a colourful abstract world far removed from our own. Inspired by the incredible loose and paintings of it’s director,
and as such asked for a very particular approach to it’s visuals and rendering. We rely on bold &lt;em&gt;‘Chiaroscuro’&lt;/em&gt; style shadows, noisy
dithered shading and bold saturated colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apartPot.png&quot; alt=&quot;apot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apartConceptArt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;apartConceptArt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apartTree.png&quot; alt=&quot;apartTree.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;procedural-animation-and-living-machines&quot;&gt;Procedural Animation and Living Machines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you journey through the world of &lt;em&gt;Apart&lt;/em&gt; you will encounter many weird and wonderful creatures who desperately need your help.
Inspired by the results of genetic locomotion experiments, and the seminal work of Karl Sims in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.karlsims.com/evolved-virtual-creatures.html&quot;&gt;Evolved Virtual Creatures&lt;/a&gt;
these creatures are found in various states of &lt;em&gt;learning to be&lt;/em&gt;. Often awkward of half formed and clumsy, but beautiful in their imperfections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not employing any actual machine learning or related techniques in our project, but we are leaning heavily into physics based
procedural animation for both the natural characterful clumsiness and interactivity that it brings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apart0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apart1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Skateboarding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apart2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/apart3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Skateboarding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Apart</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Apart</guid>
        
        <category>Designer</category>
        
        <category>Programmer</category>
        
        <category>Technical Artist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Assemble With Care</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Assemble With Care is a beautiful narrative puzzle game, that sees you restore objects that have sentimental value to
their owners, and explore their relationships to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on Assemble With Care, with a very small team, as an &lt;strong&gt;Artist&lt;/strong&gt; and the sole &lt;strong&gt;Technical Artist&lt;/strong&gt;, brought onto the 
project at the very beginning of development in order to develop a unique art style that would capture the bold painterly strokes of our concept art, in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/AWC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AWC.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by ustwo Games and relased for iOS and Android devices,
you can find out more about this game at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.assemblegame.com/&quot;&gt;assemblegame.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rendering-experiments&quot;&gt;Rendering Experiments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a challenging brief, I was tasked not only with creating a rendering style that would not only compliment and enhance the act of manipulating and reconfiguring intricate broken machinery,
but would also translate the strokes of the concept art directly to the screen. This was not about capturing the &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; of the art, but recreating it as faithfully as possible in real time 3D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our most exciting experiments used a novel post processing technique, that took a number of deferred buffers and a customisable
sampling kernel, and combined them together to reconstruct the image in the style of a loose dry brush painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/painterlygif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Painterly Rendering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the technical nature of the game, care had to be given to preserve important signifiers and attempt to reinforce readability. We gave pixels an ‘importance’ value that would allow their colour to bleed over their neighbours, highlights and black lines painted last on top of all other colours, just as a painter would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/AwcPainterlyCropped.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Painterly Rendering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/AwcCameraCropped.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Painterly Rendering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this rendering approach was pared back and we eventually decided to remove it completely due to the specific gameplay readability 
constraints of this project, I think the results are still very compelling and would be a great match for a integrating real time 3D elements into similarly
styled 2D illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/AssembleWithCare</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/AssembleWithCare</guid>
        
        <category>Technical Artist</category>
        
        <category>Artist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Monument Valley 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monument Valley 2&lt;/strong&gt; is the award winning second installment in the Monument Valley series. A followup that builds on the incredibly
strong foundation of its predecessor and uses it to tell an honest and emotional story family and motherhood.
You can find out more about this game at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.monumentvalleygame.com/mv2&quot;&gt;monumentvalleygame.com/mv2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MV2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MV2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MV2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MV2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on the &lt;strong&gt;Monument Valley 2&lt;/strong&gt; team as the sole technical artist, and animator. Over the devlopment of this title, I provided tooling, pipelines,
animation, and artist support, as well as ‘art-ing’ a handful of levels within the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is an outstanding game, a way to prove how narrative, gameplay and art design can work together to make an almost flawless experience.
&lt;cite&gt;Alberto González&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_Pride.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MV2_Pride&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MV2_1.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MV2_2.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MV2_3.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/MV2_0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MV2_0.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/MonumentValley2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/MonumentValley2</guid>
        
        <category>Technical Artist</category>
        
        <category>Artist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Red Carpet Rampage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is very silly idea the came up over a pub conversation early in 2016, ahead of the then topical upcoming Oscar awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a free-to-play arcade-style web game that puts you in the shoes of Leonardo DiCaprio as he sprints down the red carpet on his much-anticipated quest for Oscar glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put together by myself, &lt;strong&gt;Bjorn-Erik Aschim&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Sam Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;, it marks The Line’s first venture into the world of games and a fun experiment in &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; rapid development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/Shot05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s can be played here in any desktop or mobile browser. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://redcarpetrampage.com/&quot;&gt;redcarpetrampage.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While the gameplay is addictive, it’s the detail and humour of each challenge that pay dividends for players.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/general-news/why-impossible-win-an-oscar-866560/&quot;&gt;— The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rapid-design&quot;&gt;Rapid Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Carpet Rampage is a fairly uncommon artefact as a topical video game, based around events contemporary to its development and release
the idea of making a game or website was raised roughly 4 weeks before the Oscar ceremony, which gave us a tight window in which to 
deliver a surprisingly complete and feature full experience about events AS they happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/RCRNotes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oscar gundam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/RCRNotes2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shot05.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Comedy is always hard to deliver in a video game, but Leo’s Red Carpet Rampage nails it.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/archive/leo-dicaprio-oscars-2016-game&quot;&gt;— Mashable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;playful-jamming&quot;&gt;Playful jamming&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such development took a very freeform shape. The goal here was to surprise and delight, so the game is crammed full of jokes, references,
mini games and gameplay twists. Additionally all of these twists also had to work perfectly in browsers and on mobile, so with a simple collection
of input verbs, we have players switching from running and jumping, to writing essays, catching snowflakes, fighting bears and taking down enormous
Oscar themed robots, among many more, all within seconds of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may seem random and chaotic, we put a lot of thought and design work into curating and designing these elements into a complete an coherent user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/oscarGundam.png&quot; alt=&quot;oscar gundam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/Shot04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shot05.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/Shot03-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shot03-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/blaknominee.png&quot; alt=&quot;nominee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although most analysts seem to think that this is the year Leo finally catches his illusive Oscar, would it really be so bad if he didn’t and “Red Carpet Rampage” became a runaway franchise hit?
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2016/digital/news/leonardo-dicaprio-video-game-oscar-red-carpet-rampage-1201707554/&quot;&gt;— Variety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/RedCarpetRampage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/RedCarpetRampage</guid>
        
        <category>Designer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Max van der Merwe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!, I’m a London based Director, Designer, Prototyper, Programmer, Technical Artist and All Round Graphics Nerd, 
who has been working in the games and animation industry for well over a decade now! I’ve worked on award winners, 
viral sensations, big and small projects and have done so in a wide variety of different roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;work-in-animation&quot;&gt;Work In Animation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working in the animation, games and related industries, primarily in london, since 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this time I have worked on a variety of commercial animation projects and short films for clients including&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The BBC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Line Animation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric Theatre Collective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tandem Films&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blink Ink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;work-in-games&quot;&gt;Work In Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve shipped a variety of commercial games under a variety of different roles, each of these were multi year projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lands End&lt;/strong&gt; in 2015, as 3D artist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ustwogames.co.uk/games/lands-end/&quot;&gt;Offical Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monument Valley 2&lt;/strong&gt; in 2017 as a technical artist and animator. &lt;a href=&quot;MonumentValley2&quot;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assemble With Care&lt;/strong&gt; in 2019 as a technical artist, graphics programmer and production artist. &lt;a href=&quot;AssembleWithCare&quot;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alba: A WildLife adventure&lt;/strong&gt; in 2020 as a technical artist and graphics programmer. &lt;a href=&quot;Alba&quot;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desta: The Memories Between&lt;/strong&gt; 2022 as a designer, prototyper and technical artist. &lt;a href=&quot;Desta&quot;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monument Valley 3&lt;/strong&gt;, release TBC, as a technical artist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple unannounced and in development titles&lt;/strong&gt; as a variety of roles, including director, designer and prototyper with both The Line Animation and ustwo Games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 1989 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Max!</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Max!</guid>
        
        <category>Human</category>
        
        <category>Person</category>
        
        <category>Me!</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
